Guide to the Karen J. Maj collection of Will Inman papers, 1989-2003 RL.11435
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Karen J. Maj collection of Will Inman papers
1989-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Maj, Karen J.
RL.11435
0.5 Linear Feet
Collection comprises correspondence and poetry shared between Will Inman and Karen J. Maj, a student and collaborator of Inman while they were both living in Tucson, Arizona. The collection includes signed chapbooks by Inman, three issues of the poetry journal Laughing Dog Press, and information about the literary community in Tucson.
Biographical / Historical
Will Inman was a poet, essayist, editor, and publisher. He was born William Archibald McGirt, Jr. in Wilmington, North Carolina where his father, William A. McGirt, was in the insurance and real estate business and his mother, Delia E. McGirt (maiden name Inman), was a registered nurse. He attended Duke University, graduating with an A.B in 1943. After college, Inman worked as a union organizer for tobacco workers in North Carolina before moving to New York City in the late 1950s. He served as the Vice-president of Free University of New York in the mid 1960s. He has worked as an editor and publisher of various literary journals and has had his work published in numerous anthologies and literary journals as well as in individual volumes. His weekly column, Conchsound in the Hills, was published in the Franklin, PA News-Heraldin the 1960s. In addition to writing poetry, fiction, plays, and essays, Inman was also a prolific correspondent and diarist. He was active in numerous causes, including the War in Vietnam, the Civil Rights movement, gay rights, and various environmental issues. In 1956, he was questioned by the House Un-American Activities Committee as to his relationship with the Communist Party. His activism continued into the 1990s; he led writing workshops in an Arizona State Prison, as well as teaching writing to the homeless in transition. Inman died October 3, 2009.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Karen J. Maj collection of Will Inman papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift from Karen J. Maj in 2017.
Related Materials
The Rubenstein Library also holds the Will Inman papers and the Will Inman Correspondence with Steven Finch collection.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises correspondence and poetry shared between Will Inman and Karen J. Maj, a student and collaborator of Inman while they were both living in Tucson, Arizona. The collection includes signed chapbooks by Inman, three issues of the poetry journal Laughing Dog Press, and information about the literary community in Tucson.
Poets, American -- Correspondence; Tucson (Ariz.); Inman, Will, 1923-2009; Laughing Dog Press
- Correspondence plus poems, 1998-2003 (Box 1)
- Photograph of Will, 2000 (Box 1)
- Poem to Karen and Lyn/ Karen to Will, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
- Program booklet, poetry readings by members of the poetry workshop Tuscon UU, 2001 (Box 1)
- Earth's Daughters, 2001 (Box 1)
- Poets Against the War/ Poem: "A War-Start to Lose", 2003 March 3 (Box 1)
- The Laughing Dog, literary journal, 2000-2001; 3 folders (Box 1)
- Arizona Daily Star, Article from Karen regarding Tucson literary scene, 1999 (Box 1)
- Chapbook signed, "Surfing the Dark Sound, Sacred Chaff, Center Waking", 1998 (Box 1)
- Chapbook signed, "End of the Ceaseless Road", 1999 September 3 (Box 1)
- Chapbook signed, "An Other Eye, Other Ear", 2000 (Box 1)
- Chapbook signed, "A Resonance of Begetting", 2001 (Box 1)
- Chapbook signed, "Seth, a Way Through", 2001 (Box 1)
- Arizona poems, 1986-2001; 10 folders (Box 1)
- Small Press review of "End of the Ceaseless Road", 2000 (Box 1)
- Poems noted as accepted for publication: Minotaur, House Organ, Earth's Daughters, The Lucid Stone, 1989-2003 (Box 1)